<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<QuotesList>
    <Fishing>
        <Quote id="F1">The texas rig is a good rig for casting worms and other soft body baits into weedy, snag prone areas.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F2">Largemouth Bass are voracious eaters, consuming everything from Blue Gill to bats.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F3">Largemouth Bass come in two subspecies, the longer lived Northern Largemouth and the larger growing Florida Bass.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F4">Largemouth bass are native to limited freshwater ranges in the Central and Eastern United States, but do to popularity amongst anglers, have spread across the US and around the world.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F5">Largemouth bass are ambush predators and like to stay near places they can hide in, like sunken logs or dense weeds.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F6">If you’re after bass, go for weed-less baits.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F7">Northern Pike and Bass are cannibals.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F8">The biggest Largemouth Bass ever caught weighed 22 lbs. [2.2 lbs to the kg]</Quote>
        <Quote id="F9">Fly fishing uses false casting with a long pole and weighted fishing line to cast super light, top water baits.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F10">Fly fishers makes use of artificial baits that mimic insects in various stages of development to lure fish that like to eat drowning bugs.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F11">Good things come to those who bait.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F12">One of the best ways to catch trout is to fly fish.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F13">Look for small surface feeding birds to find good spots to fly fish.  More birds means more insects around and better chance of getting a bite!</Quote>
        <Quote id="F14">When fly fishing, look for bugs on the water, that’s what the fish are looking for.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F15">The fish aren’t all hiding in deep water, many fish take shelter and hunt in the shallows and weeds.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F16">If you’re fishing the shore, try not to stand too close to the bank, especially in clear water. The fish might spot you and get spooked.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F17">Braided line is generally lighter and stronger than monofilament line, however, it doesn’t stretch so it’s up to your rod to absorb shocks.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F18">It’s not that the fish aren’t biting today, it’s that they aren’t biting for you.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F19">Catawba worms make great bait, so if you’re ever in the right part of the American South, make sure to get some.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F20">Bluegill go by a lot of different names: bream, brim, perch, sunfish, sun perch, spiny bream. Only one of those is fake.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F21">Some freshwater mussels use bluegill’s gills as a refuge before finding a place to settle.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F22">Bluegill are usually about 7.5 inches [1 inch to 2.54 cm] and less than 4 pounds [2.2 kg to the pound].</Quote>
        <Quote id="F23">Male bluegills make bowl shaped nests in the sand.  There females deposit their eggs and males fan water over the eggs to keep them clean and oxygenated.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F24">Male bluegill build nests in groups. Sometimes these clusters exceed over 50 individual nests.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F25">Bluegills live 5 or 8 years on average [1 year to the year].</Quote>
        <Quote id="F26">Bluegills are good pan fish.  If you catch a couple, they’re good eating.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F27">Bluegill like to school, so where there’s one, there’s probably several more.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F28">The best time to catch Bluegill is at dawn or dusk.  They like hunting in dim conditions.  On the other hand, they’ll also bite anything they find so, it won’t be difficult to catch them during the day either.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F29">Bluegill breed aggressively, so don’t feel bad about making a few of them dinner.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F30">Bluegill eat anything: insects, water plants, minnows, crustaceans, peanut butter and jelly sandwiches…</Quote>
        <Quote id="F31">Muskellunge, or Muskies, are large freshwater fish that often weight almost 40 pounds [You know the conversion].</Quote>
        <Quote id="F32">You can eat Muskie, but I can’t think of a single person I know that has.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F33">Muskie are fun fish to catch, they fight hard and for a long time.  Hooking a muskie is a commitment.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F34">Muskie are ambush predators and rely on sight, thus they like clear-ish water (but not too clear) and are more active during the day.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F35">Muskies will breach the water’s surface to ruin the day of unsuspecting frogs, ducks, and muskrats.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F36">Muskies can eat prey up to two thirds their body length and they are not afraid to attack creatures bigger than that.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F37">Muskies were purpose made to break the rods and line of unsuspecting anglers.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F38">Muskies like active bait with high movement.  They’re also particular about the type of feed they bite depending on the time of year and the forage in their area.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F39">The best way to catch muskie is to use 15 pound test and a light rod.  Next, blissfully think to yourself that you’re looking forward to a relaxing day on the lake.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F40">The best time to catch muskie is in the fall.  Make sure you’ve got a strong hook.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F41">How do you catch catfish: I don’t know, you just do?  There’s a billion species of them. Use something smelly, they’ll bite.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F42">Do you have a pole, some line, a hook, and something that smells like death? Congratulations you just caught a catfish.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F43">Catfish exists to delude young people into thinking that all fish are easy to catch and delicious, thus convincing them to waste years of their lives fishing.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F44">As a general rule of thumb, fish go to the shallows when it’s cool, and deep water when it’s hot: the deep midday and the shallows at night.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F45">Seriously, I’m not giving you catfish tips, go figure it out.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F46">Walleye are… what, did you think I was joking?  Yes I am just going to move on.  We’re done talking about catfish.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F47">Spinning reels are a good choice for beginners.  They’re cheap, easy to operate, easy to clean, and good at handling light to medium weight fish.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F48">Baitcasting reels are more expensive and may require you to manage more aspects of the operation (like properly distributing the line on the spool), but are generally lighter per length of line carried and much stronger.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F49">Spincasting reels are never a good choice. Just say no.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F50">Trolling reels are built to allow you to drag the line behind your boat.  They exist to be abused: chemically, thermally, and kinetically.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F51">Walleye have milky eyes due to a reflective surface in their eye that helps them see in low light conditions.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F52">Walleye like to hunt at dawn and dusk, but have no problem hunting at night due to their specially adapted eyes.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F53">Walleye are originally from Canada and the North Central US, but have been spread around the US as game fish.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F54">Walleye spend the day in the cool, undisturbed deep, hiding from that eternal scourge, the sun.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F55">Based on their behavior you’d think Walleye subsist on chips and energy drinks, but it turns out they prefer invertebrates, small fish, and such.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F56">Walleye tend to live about 10 years or so and can get up to 30 to 36 inches long [2.54 cm to the inch].</Quote>
        <Quote id="F57">Walleye have a spiny front dorsal fin.  Mind your hands.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F58">Consensus is that walleye are pretty tasty.  They’re usually between 3 and 6 pounds [2.2 pounds to the kilogram].</Quote>
        <Quote id="F59">There doesn’t seem to be a magic bullet with Walleye, just be sure to bring earthworms and a jigging rig.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F60">Walleye can be caught year round, but aim for the night time or a cloudy day to improve your chances.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F61">Wear gloves and sunblock, it’s just stupid not to.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F62">Give your fellow fishers space.  There’s nothing worse than having someone park their pole right on top of you.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F63">There are plenty of other fish in the ocean, you have no excuse for seeking out Goliath Groupers.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F64">Many popular saltwater fish species are endangered, so fish responsibly and consult your local fish and game authorities on what you can keep.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F65">Blue fish, also known as shad, elf, and tailor, are found across the world in warm and temperate oceans.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F66">Blue fish are aggressive hunters and are know for sporting a set of sharp teeth.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F67">Blue fish group in large schools where they put their toothy grins to good effect ripping through bait balls.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F68">Blue fish will bite most common ocean rigs, they prefer live bate, but are by no means picky.</Quote>
        <Quote id="F69">Be careful when reeling in blue fish, they will fight, and when you’ve caught them, they will bite!</Quote>
        <Quote id="F70">Blue fish can’t be frozen and don’t store well, so if you catch to eat, eat them asap.</Quote>
    </Fishing>
    <Real>
        <Quote id="R1">The rook is the horse one.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R2">The Spanish Opening is one of the first openings taught to new chess players.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R3">The Queen’s 9 points, that’s final.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R4">The farther a piece is from its color’s king, the smarter it is.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R5">The pawns are peasant levies, so the more of them you lose, the more your economy will suffer.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R6">Pawns are situationally very powerful: they can promote, attack en passant, and, in numbers, can deny areas of the board.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R7">Sometimes it is strategically advantageous to bait you opponent with a piece to set up the development of a different piece.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R8">The Berlin Defense is the funniest way to inform your opponent that you are a civil engineer.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R9">If you can’t think of anything else, move a knight or a pawn to open. You came here without a plan, what have you got to lose?</Quote>
        <Quote id="R10">A chess match trains your enemy how to beat you, thus in order to avoid giving the opposition an advantage the only reasonable course of action is to not play the match.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R11">Chess is a horror game from the king’s perspective.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R12">Try asking your bishop to convince the opponent’s bishop to excommunicate the opponent’s king.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R13">Have you attempted to negotiate an armistice? That might give you enough time to come up with a plan.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R14">Castling can get you out of a pinch, it’s a shame you can only do it once.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R15">The Bishop can be a hard piece to develop and leverage effectively. Moving the king or queen side pawn can be pretty critical to this end.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R16">Having a lone pawn in the center of the board is not necessarily a bad thing.  It’s still denying moves and creating opportunities.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R17">Knights are better than Bishops in the early game, when more pieces are on the board, but as things open up, Bishops dominate.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R18">When you play chess, you are not the king, you are a cruel supernatural force that compels the king to engage in bloody and fruitless wars.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R19">Put your rook on an open file. Just try it, trust me.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R20">In 1255 it was decided that pawns would only move forward due to desertion concerns.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R21">A forking attack, is a move that has the potential to open two of your opponent’s pieces up to capture.  Thus if your opponent moves one piece, the other is lost.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R22">Pick an opening and stick with it, you’ll figure out how to adapt later.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R23">To pin a piece is to attack it in such a fashion that moving that piece would expose another piece to attack.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R24">In the original version of chess, the A2 and A7 pawns were actually vikingers from the far North.  Unfortunately, they never seemed to understand the rules.  They’d steal from the bishops, kill pawns, and leave the board.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R25">You only need two rooks to checkmate.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R26">If you don’t like the way the AI plays, it’s entirely your fault.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R27">You might find it handy to familiarize yourself with common checkmate patterns. It’ll help in the end game.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R28">You’re probably very familiar with chump checks.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R29">Rooks have a low chance of surrendering due to spoiled grain stores and plague, thus waiting for poor weather on the opponent’s side of the board can proffer a default points lead.</Quote>
        <Quote id="R30">Chess is just a scheme to sell you chess instructional materials.</Quote>
    </Real>
    <Special>
        <Quote id="Sp1">Perhaps the conflict is not with your opponent.</Quote>
        <Quote id="Sp2">You ever cast, and cast, and cast, all day long just to find you never really cared about catching anything in the first place?  It was about the water wasn’t it? Something in the blue…</Quote>
        <Quote id="Sp3">How long have you been here?</Quote>
        <Quote id="Sp4">When do you truly cross the border into competence?  Will you ever really know?</Quote>
        <Quote id="Sp5">“Fail” comes from the Old French “falir.”  It means what you might expect: to come up short, to terminate unsuccessfully.</Quote>
        <Quote id="Sp6">In order to succeed you must have a goal.  What is your goal?</Quote>
        <Quote id="Sp7">I really don’t think there’s much to be achieved here.  I think academics have a bad habit of ascribing too much of importance to their hobbies.</Quote>
        <Quote id="Sp8">There are two ways to read Sisyphus: the avarice and lack humility of man motivates them to lash out against inevitable fate or that even selfish, small men have a chance to beat what seems inevitable and that every opportunity has merit.</Quote>
        <Quote id="Sp9">Do you think the gods of fate like salty or sour things more?</Quote>
        <Quote id="Sp10">Are you even reading these anymore?</Quote>
    </Special> 
</QuotesList>
